《大白鲨2》
快 快
Come on, come on.
（阿米堤奖学基金启动舞会）
- 你到哪里去了？- 耽搁了
- Where have you been? - Delayed.
我知道 对我来说是件大事
That I figured. This is a big deal for me.
韩卓拿走了吉普车钥匙 我找不到备用的
Hendricks had the keys to the Jeep. I couldn't find the spares.
装作你一直在这里
Listen, act as if you've been here the whole time.
- 怎么装？- 不耐烦
- How? - Look bored.
多谢阿米堤高中乐队 精彩的表演
Thank you Amity High School Band for that eloquent selection.
我们很高兴 继续
We're happy, once again…
妈 麦克拒绝跟我讲话
Mama, Michael won't talk to me.
- 你在这里干什么？- 施太太没有来 没事的
- What are you doing here? - Mrs Silvera couldn't come.
有请今年的阿米堤小姐韦迪娜
And now this year's Miss Amity, Tina Wilcox,
为这座新酒店正式剪彩
will cut the ribbon, officially opening this luxurious new hotel.
这株摇钱树 是由海滩公寓的建筑者
This money tree is donated by Len Peterson,
兰尼一皮德逊捐赠
the builder of Amity Shores Condominiums,
以此作为对社区的回馈
as a gesture of goodwill.
现在恭请兰尼先生
Let's hear it for Len.
谢谢你 兰尼
Thanks, Len.
一千五百美元
$1, 500.
捐赠给阿米堤奖学基金
as a special gift to the Amity Scholarship Fund.
迪娜 来 剪彩
Go ahead, Tina, cut it.
谢谢你
Atta girl.
现在再请阿米堤高中乐队表演
And now the Amity High School Band once again.
平台上有茶点招待各位
Refreshments on the patio, everyone.
嗯 孩子 我们走
Oh, boy. Let's go.
布迪 你好啊？
Brody, how are you?
你好 马丁
Hello, Martin.
- 我说讲演真精彩 - 莱瑞 棒极了
- I think it went well. - Hell of a speech, Larry.
太好了 捐赠绝对正确
Right on the money.
多谢 见过我儿子了吗？
Thank you. Have you met my son Larry?
- 没有 - 莱瑞 你过来
- No. - Larry Jr. Larry, over here.
跟兰尼打个招呼
Here we go. Say hello to Len.
- 你好 - 嗨 莱瑞
- How you doing? - Hi, Larry.
- 多漂亮的孩子 - 谢谢
- Nice-looking boy. - Thank you.
爱伦 看看酒吧开了没有 别怠慢了客人
Ellen, make sure that the bar is open and everyone's taken care of.
好的
Sure.
先生 真了不起的女人
Yes, sir, a fantastic lady.
- 没有她我不知道会怎么样 - 真的？我也是啊
- Don't know what I'd do without her. - Really? Neither do I.
- 你表妹多大？- 十七 是高中生
- How old is your cousin? - 17. She's a senior.
我不喜欢不认识约会
I'm not crazy about blind dates.
如果她们屁股和胸脯 长得不错也无妨
They're OK if they got little white canes and tin cups.
- 真恶心！- 真讨厌！
- That's awful! - Ah, what the hell?
- 是你妈安排的吗？- 对 这是她的工作
- Did your mom put all this together? - Yeah, it's her job.
- 饮料是她调配的吗？- 不是
- Did she make the punch? - No.
那好 真难喝
Good, it's terrible.
- 你有舞伴吗？- 没有
- Get your dance? - Nope.
- 我也没有 - 你打算邀请谁呢？
- Me neither. - Who you gonna ask next?
韦迪娜 阿迪的女朋友
Tina Wilcox. Ed's girlfriend.
你疯了？
You're crazy.
问一声也无妨 有时美女也很寂寞
It doesn't hurt to ask. Sometimes beautiful girls are the loneliest.
简直是胡说八道
That's a crock of shit.
我知道
I know.
到泽西海滩这是 第四还是第五晚上？
Was it the fourth or fifth night at the Jersey shore?
第四晚上
The fourth!
- 我以为你不尊重我 - 我尊重！
- I thought you wouldn't respect me. - I did! I did!
我们出去好吧？
Why don't we get out of here?
什么？出去逛逛？
What? To fool around?
- 为什么不？- 听你的
- Why not? - You're on.
这个水管沾满了贝壳
This pipe has more barnacles than you do.
你在做什么？我告诉你！
What are you doing? I told you!
扫到你左边儿！另一边儿
Brush it off to your left! Your other left.
我想你今天休假
I thought you were off duty.
早安 上午是我个人的时间
Good morning! Till noon I'm on my own time.
- 嗨 警长！- 什么？
- Hey, Chief! - Yeah?
在主航道发现了一艘大游艇
We got a gold plater in the main channel, a big cruiser.
- 在哪里？- 在那里
- Whereabouts? - Off the point.
没有灯光 只有潜水旗
No running lights, just the diver's flag.
- 要我去看看吗？- 你可以吗？我开不了这个
- Want me to run out there? - Would you? I can't run this thing!
- 乐意前往 - 办公室见
- Happy to do it. - I'll see you back at the office.
带这老头子一起去
Take the old man of the sea.
先解船头缆 再解尾缆
Cast off the bowline, and then the stern line,
然后解侧缆
and then cast off the spring line.
出发！
Let's go!
我们只逗留几分钟
We'll only be here for a few minutes.
- 我可以跟你一起去吗？- 不行
- Can't I come with you? - No.
- 他可以跟我去 - 不行
- He can come with me. - No.
- 不行？- 不行 下船
- No? - No. Off the boat.
他起码可以帮助我
He can help me, at least.
好！好兄弟！
Boo! Big brothers!
尚 你驶过船吗？
Hey, Sean, ever been an anchor before?
- 麦克 嗨 - 要出海吗？
- Mike, hi. - You going out now?
- 不 - 好 你可以见见我表妹
- No. - Good, you can meet my cousin.
别担心 我会见到她的
Don't worry, I'll meet her.
汤姆 回头见 周四同样时间
OK, Tom, see you later. Same time Thursday.
阿迪 过来
Andy, over here.
回头见
See you guys later.
- 怎么啦？- 不怎么啦！
- What's the problem? - What isn't?!
布露！布露
Brooke!
杰克 嗨
Jackie, hi.
你说 她是谁？
Quick, quick, who's that?
- 我堕入爱河了！- 那个表妹 我希望
- I'm in love! - The cousin, I hope.
真幸运 幸运…
Lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky…
看见她看你的眼神吗？
Did you see the way she looked at you?
- 她想得到你 - 她不是在看我
- She wants you. - She wasn't looking at me.
什么？她看着你直流口水
What? She was staring at you and drooling.
不 我又瘦又戴眼镜
No, I'm thin, I wear glasses,
我住在阿米堤岛多年了
I live in Amity Island year round.
我配不上她
I'm not good enough for her.
你说得对 她也许不是在看你
You're right, she probably wasn't looking at you.
莱瑞 你看 莱瑞 看！
Larry, look. Larry, look!
- 什么？- 你看她
- What? - Look at her.
见到你很高兴
Good to see you!
- 嗯？- 她的乳头像个麻雀
- Well? - She's got tits like a sparrow.
你怎么能这样说？
Do you have to talk like that?
你是谁 我妈妈？打开主帆
What are you, my mother? Undo the jib.
- 我们去驾船 - 驾船？
- We're going sailing. - Sailing?
我想要你认识这个人 他很帅
He's cute.
瞧 我在走！他在晒他的脚底板
Hey, look, I'm walking!
麦克 过来
Mike, over here.
道格拉斯！
Douglas!
我不能看新闻 球赛 甚至连电影也不能看了
I can't watch the news, a ball game, can't even watch a movie.
只听到那些孩子通话器的声音
All I hear is that kid and his radio going "breaker, breaker".
我会尽力而为的
I'll try but it's under federal jurisdiction.
但受到联邦法例管制
Call the FBI.
通知联邦调查局一个个来 你俩跟布莉谈 你跟我来
One at a time. You two talk to Polly, you come with me.
- 金雷丝怎么啦？- 她的卧室窗户对着我儿子的
- What's this about Grace Kinny? - Her bedroom window faces my son's.
她勾引他 裹着毛巾跳舞
She's teasing him, dancing around in a towel.
跳舞？韩卓，这边走 对不起
Dancing? Hendricks, good. Right this way. Excuse us.
来看看这个九零八
Come in here and check out this 908.
什么九零八？我从来没听说过
What the hel"s a 908? I never heard of a 908.
九零八是帮我脱身的意思
908 means get me out of there.
- 这是什么 - 游艇潜水员的摄影机
- What's that? - Diver's camera from the cruiser.
弃置的游艇！
Oh, the abandoned cruiser!
来自罗德岛的富家子弟
Rich guys from Newport, Rhode Island.
如果我有艘价值十万的游艇 我不会丢弃的
If I had a $100, 000 boat, I wouldn't abandon it.
如果你有一艘 那就会被人调查的
If you had one, there'd be an investigation.
- 真风趣 - 她令我儿子神魂颠倒！
- Very funny. - It's driving my boy to distraction!
- 去调查一下儿跳舞 - 跳舞？
- Dancing! Check out this dance. - Dance?
- 我还可以再上去吗？- 让他上去
- Can I go back up? - Take it back up.
上去 麦克！
Now, back up, Mike!
麦克 缠住了
Mike, it's twisted.
拉上来 麦克
Pull it up, Mike.
- 在你下面 麦克 - 现在放下来
- Underneath you, Mike. - Drop it down now.
你没事吧？
You OK?
拉下来！麦克
Pull down, Mike.
天气继续温暖晴朗
'The weather continues to be warm and clear.
请接着收听全日音乐节目，新英格兰摇滚乐
'Back to the 24- hour music from Plymouth, the rock of New England. '
等等 休息一会儿吧
Wait, take a break for a minute, OK?
迪娜 你去哪里？
Tina… where are you going?
嗨
Hey!
阿迪 来 我们去滑水
Eddie, come on, let's go sking.
- 什么？- 我们可以用我叔叔的船
- What? - We can use my uncle's boat.
下周去 好吗？
We'll do it next week, OK?
你总爱推到下周
With you everything is next week.
泰利？
Terry?
不
No!
哇
Wow!
天啦
God!
我找不到任何人 一定在海底或漂走了
I can't find anyone. They must have gone to the bottom and drifted.
目击者见到一人驾船 一人滑水
Witnesses say there was one person in the boat and one water-sking.
我跟你说 这里什么也没有
'I told you, there's nothing here. '
我要你继续搜索
I want you to try dragging.
搜索多久？浪很急 天也快黑了
For how long? The current's moving everything and it'll be dark soon.
我不管 我要你呆到查出结果
I don't care, I want you to stay on it as long as it takes.
十、四
10-4.
我们听到一声巨响 接着看到一股黑烟
We heard a noise like a boom. Then there was this cloud of smoke.
爆炸了 一分钟前 还好好的 但…
The explosion. One minute they were having a wonderful time, the next…
你知道是怎么爆炸的吗？
You've no idea what could have caused it?
不知道是什么引起的
I don't know what could have done that.
- 他们是游客吗？- 不知道
- Were they off islanders? - I don't know.
我们可以走了吗？
Can we go now?
警长？
Chief?
布迪警长 可以走了吗？
Chief Brody, can we go, please?
可以 谢谢 迪娜
Yes, thank you, Tina.
我们在这里搜索几遍了
We've been over this a dozen times.
我知道 知道
I know, I know.
- 还要呆多久？- 直到有所发现为止
- How much longer? - Until we find something.
我很冷 无聊
I'm cold, bored.
你无聊！
YOU'RE bored.
他妈的！
Holy shit!
乔治
George!
上帝 很重
Jesus, this is heavy!
倒霉 放下它
Aw, shit. Drop it.
- 这是什么？- 是电缆 放下它
- What is it? - Drop it. It's a power line.
- 太棒了！- 我们解开它
- Terrific - Let me untangle it.
别让全岛断电
We don't want a power blackout.
趁没发生什么前离开吧
Let's go before we do find something.
这是你第三支烟了
That's your third smoke already.
- 就着咖啡 - 吃个甜饼吧
- With coffee. - Try a donut.
- 我要吃杂果圈 - 吃奇乐饼吧
- I want Froot Loops. - Eat Cheerios.
你吃奇乐饼 我吃杂果圈
You eat Cheerios, I want Froot Loops.
你吃奇乐饼
You eat Cheerios.
你们今天干什么？
What are you guys up to today?
- 我去驾船 - 又去？
- I'm going sailing. - Again?
- 还能做什么？- 那个工作怎么样？
- What else is there to do? - What about that job?
我真的要工作吗？
Do I have to?
他不必工作 现在是假期
He doesn't have to. It is his vacation.
我的记事本放在哪里了？
Where did I leave my date book?
早安 各位今天这么早
Good morning. Everybody's up early today.
有什么事吗？
Something going on?
很多 这孩子十七岁了 我们说过要他找个工作
Lots. This kid is 17. We've talked about him getting a job before.
对 希望你能花点儿时间陪他
You're right. I wish you could spend some time with him.
我怎么可以呢？有宗船只意外
How can I? I've got a boat accident.
我只有三名下属 一个迷于警艇的副手
I've only got three cops and a deputy in love with the police launch.
现在又有宗案子 每个人都迷恋驾船？
And here's another one. Everybody's a boat freak?
这是个岛屿啊
It's an island.
- 我走了 - 等一会儿
- I'm going. - Hold it. Wait a minute.
风浪太大就别出去得太远 已经有不少麻烦了
Don't go out too far if it's rough. We've had a lot of trouble.
- 好 回头见 - 要小心
- OK. See you later. - Be careful.
我会的
I'll be careful.
- 迪娜 回来 - 不！
- Tina, come back here. - Nope!
- 把帽子还给我 - 不！
- Give me my hat. - No!
快回来 迪娜！
Come on, Tina!
回来
Come back here.
我不明白他们怎么出来了
I wonder why they decided to move.
- 灯塔内太热了 - 他俩会嫌热？！
- Too hot in the lighthouse? - Too hot for those two?!
哟
Yuck.
一接到消息我马上通知了你 听说伤口确实很大
I called you as soon as I heard. I hear the bites are really big.
- 先看看再说吧 - 好
- After we've looked, we'll talk. - OK.
是这里
Here it is.
请大家退后一点儿
Could you move back, please?
让我们透透气吧 请退后一点儿 谢谢
Move back. Please just move back. Thanks.
天啊
Jesus.
你看怎么回事？
What do you think?
按步就班吧
First things first.
先量鼻翼
Tip of the snout, please.
- 好 七米半 - 七米半？
- OK. Seven and a half meters. - Seven and a half meters?
对
Correct.
- 检查伤口的大小 - 什么？
- Check the bite radius. - The what?
- 口的形状 - 鲸鱼的口？
- The shape of the mouth. - Whale's mouth?
- 鲨鱼的口 - 什么鲨鱼？
- Shark's mouth. - What shark?
咬它的鲨鱼
The shark that did this.
我们并不知道 对不对？
We don't know that, do we?
- 这正是我们来调查的原因 - 好
- That's what we're here to find out. - And we will.
你声音太小我听不见
I can't hear you if you whisper.
一百一十一厘米
111 centimetres.
六十八
68.
我对鲨鱼有一定的经验
I've had some experience with sharks.
啊，是吗？
Oh, have you?
我看是大白鲨干的
Yeah. And I think a great white might have done this.
- 大白鲨？- 对
- Carcharodon carcharias? - Right.
你怎么会想到这里有大白鲨？
What makes you think there might be one in these waters?
很明显这条鱼是被大鱼咬的
It's obvious a big fish took a bite out of this big fish.
这是甫乳类动物 不是鱼
This is a mammal, not a fish.
别吹毛求疵了 是不是鲨鱼咬的？
Don't quibble! Is it a shark bite or isn't it?
有可能
Possibly.
但这是条逆戈鲸
But this is a killer whale.
那个鲨鱼一定不小
It would have to be a shark of considerable size.
我们知道血会吸引鲨鱼
We know sharks are attracted by blood and thrashing about.
声音
And sound.
声音？
Sound?
声音 像声纳或雷达
Sound, like sonar or radar.
它们喜欢不寻常不规律的声音
They hone in on unusual, irregular sounds.
有节奏和低频率的震动
Any rhythmic, low-frequency vibration.
那附近可能有一条？
So there could be one around?
不一定 可能是在别处受伤的
Not necessarily. These wounds could have been inflicted out to sea.
没有马上死 浪把它带到这里
None were immediately fatal. The currents could have carried it in.
- 今年浪很大 - 去照顾人群吧！
- We got a hell of a tide. - Just take care of the crowd!
爸爸？
Dad?
韩卓先生 请记下来
Mr Hendricks, take this down, please.
- 今天不准出海 - 我们是驾船来的
- No more sailing today, OK? - We came out in my boat.
- 安迪会驶回去的 - 我有约会
- Andy'll take it back. - I got a date.
- 她会明白的 - 她不会
- She'll understand. - She won't.
麦克 让我清静一下 好吗？
Mike, give me a break, will you?
不是大白鲨就是另一条逆戈鲸
It's either a great white or another killer whale.
我想知道是哪个
I'd like to know which.
很难根据这个尸体下结论
It's impossible to tell with that body.
它已经在此十二个小时了 至少在海上漂泊了一天
The anima"s been ashore for 12 hours and drifting for a day at least.
海中的小鱼也咬过他
Every nibbler in the sea's taken a bite.
我知道海豚会发讯号联系
I know dolphins communicate. I mean, they send signals.
如果一个鲨鱼被害 另一个会不会来…
If a shark was destroyed, could another shark come and…
鲨鱼不像人懂得报复
Sharks don't take things personally, Mr Brody.
- 爸爸 我能… - 不行
- Dad, can I… - No.
放心 我把船驶回去栓在码头
Don't worry, I'll take it back and tie it up at the docks.
- 再见 麦克 - 对不起 再见
- Bye, Mike. - I'm sorry. Bye.
- 明天见 - 我很感激 多谢
- I'll see you tomorrow. - I appreciate it. Thanks.
莱瑞 等等
Larry. Larry, wait a minute.
我要处理租赁的事情 看来今夏的生意会不错
I'm showing summer rentals, I think we have a good season going for us.
很好 但我想单独跟你谈谈
Swell. But I have to talk to you alone.
现在就可以
We're alone.
我们可能又有个鲨鱼了
We may have another shark problem.
- 你是认真的？- 我是认真的
- Are you serious? - You bet I'm serious.
沙滩上发现被吃掉一半的鲸鱼 还有两人失踪
I've got a half-eaten whale on the beach, got two persons missing.
那条鲸鱼被咬掉了这么大
The whale's got a bite out of it this big.
没人看到鲨鱼 你现实点儿
No one has seen a shark. Be realistic.
应当通知议员 虽然只是种感觉 但…
The selectmen should know about it. It's just a feeling, but…
莱瑞 不仅是这个 还…
Larry, I not only have this attack but I've got…
- 还有两个滑水… - 是个悲剧 船事故
- I've got two water-skiers… - A tragedy, but a boating accident.
没有鲨鱼 是个意外
No fin, no sharks. A boating accident.
- 可仍没找到他们 - 很多人死在这里
- They're both still missing. - We have a lot of deaths.
找不到尸体
that never turn up.
他们都被鲨鱼吃了吗？
Are they all shark victims?
可能是的
Maybe they are.
- 胡说 - 胡说？
- Bullshit. - Bullshit?
海滩上的鲸鱼伤口大是胡说？
Is it bullshit I got a whale with a bite in it this big?
你当我是傻瓜？
What am I? An ass?
你通知我时 我通知了爱伊琴和她上司
When you called me, I called Elkins and her bosses.
她不能证明有鲨鱼
Nothing she saw is proof of anything.
那我们不会采取行动？
So we're not going to do anything?
马丁，这次就不要勉强了
Martin, don't press it this time.
我要回去工作了
Well, I've got to get back to work.
好的 但你要记住今天的谈话
OK, Larry, but you just remember this conversation.
你要记住！
You just remember it!
警长？
Chief?
什么
Yeah.
警长？
Chief?
在殡仪馆找不到你
Hi. Missed you at the funeral home.
山度说你在这里
Santos said you'd be here.
是啊，克雷 一团糟
Yeah. Christ, what a mess.
你没猜错
You didn't miss much.
身份证明了？
Positive ID?
肯定是船上那个女人的
We're pretty sure it was the woman aboard the boat.
什么
Yeah?
谢谢接线员 请继续试接
Thank you, operator. Just keep trying.
- 两名潜水员有消息吗？- 没有
- Anything new on those two divers? - Nothing.
- 应当阻止游客去… - 你看过那些东西了吗？
- We should keep sightseers… - Did you look at that stuff?
- 没有 - 这部摄影机呢？
- No. - How about that camera?
- 里面可能有线索 - 对
- Might be something in it. - Yeah, right.
- 送去冲洗 - 明早就去办
- Take it to get developed. - First thing in the morning.
- 为啥现在不去？- 太晚了
- Why not now? - It's too late.
克雷 我吃饭要晚了
Christ, I'm late for dinner.
我在等一个长途电话 叫他打到我家吧
I'm expecting a long distance call. Send it to the house.
好的 警长
OK, Chief.
是 我能听到
Yes, I can hear you.
好 我会通知他的 谢谢
Yes, I'll give him the message. Thank you.
找我的？
That for me?
- 嗨 爸爸 - 嗨 小伙子
- Hi, Dad. - Hi, gang.
嗯 是曼胡珀
Well, sort of. Matt Hooper.
他在南极洲澳罗拉研究船上
He's on a vessel in the Antarctic.
明春之前无法电讯联系
and won't be in radio range till spring.
对 我曾给他打过电话
Yeah. I gave him a call.
马丁？
Martin?
嗯？
Yeah?
你情绪很低 今天去哪儿了？
You're a mess. Where were you?
去山度那儿了 在海里找到了个尸体
Over at Santos', I dragged a body out of the ocean today.
知道怎么回事了吗？
Have you any idea what happened?
不知道
No, we don't know.
山度认为是船意外的遇害者
Santos thinks it might be a victim from the boat accident.
你想谈谈此事吗？
Do you wanna talk about it?
像往常一样
Just routine.
好的
OK.
麦克 过来一下儿？
Hey, Mike, come here a minute.
什么事
What is it?
- 明天有事要你做 - 我已经有安排了
- Something for you to do tomorrow. - I kinda had plans.
出海？不行 你不能出海
Sailing? Forget it. You're grounded. Beach, that's it.
- 海滩 只能在海滩 - 别这样 爸爸
- Come on, Dad. - I talked to John.
我跟阿章说了 他沙滩有份工作你干到开学
He's got a job till you go back to school.
整个暑假
That's all summer.
他想工作 现在有了 我要那条船离开水面
He wanted a job, now he's got one. And I want that boat out the water.
- 爸爸 我能… - 明天晚上 我是认真的
- Dad, can I…? - Tomorrow night. And I mean it.
人都到齐了吗？
Now… Everybody here?
- 差不多 - 好
- Just about. - OK, terrific.
朋友们 这是本镇的海滩
Folks, this is the town beach.
开发区自然有其独自的通道
The development, naturally, has its own private access,
但我想让大家看看它的特区
but I wanted you to see the concession area.
看看这里的沙粒 像砂糖一样
Take a look at the sand. It's like sugar.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
夏季落日时
In the summertime, at sunset,
海滩美不胜收
the whole beach looks incredible.
简直令人心旷神怡
It can be absolutely breathtaking.
你会发现这个站台很有意思 我们很骄傲…
You'll find this little bandstand interesting. We take pride in this…
嗨 推销更多的好生活？
Hello. Selling more of the good life?
- 对 这里一块 那里一块 - 你丈夫在上面
- Yeah. Piece of this, piece of that. - Your husband's here.
- 他在干什么？- 这是他的工作
- What's he doing? - His job.
- 你爸叫你工作？- 对
- Dad got you working, huh? - Yeah.
- 我在帮他 - 好
- I'm helping. - Good.
你爸爸在哪里？
Do you happen to know where your dad is?
他在上面
He's up there.
我的天啊！
For Christ's sake.
如果你们有任何娱乐的问题
If you have any questions about recreational possibilities,
爱伦·布迪将乐意为各位解答
Ellen Brody will be happy to answer them.
- 跟你说句话 行吗？- 对不起
- Can I speak to you? - Excuse me a moment.
莱瑞 我们有些主顾了
Larry, we've got some live ones.
布迪在暸望塔上
Brody's riding his tower.
妈的！
Oh, shit.
你不错啊，宝贝儿
You got it, sweetheart.
快点！
Come on!
- 这还不够快吗？- 不够
- This fast enough for you? - No, faster.
- 快点儿！- 快点儿！
- Faster? - Faster!
看 我爹在那里
Hey, look! There's my dad.
向我儿子挥手
Wave to my son.
好
Good.
怎么把他弄下来？
How do we get him down from there?
也许没人注意他
Well, maybe nobody noticed.
叫他们回到车上吧？
Let's get them back in the van, huh?
好 来吧
Yeah, come on.
那个人在上面做什么？
What's that man doing way up there?
哪个人？
What man?
他在观望 在观看
Oh, he's watching. You know, a lookout.
为什么？
For what?
这是个观鲨塔 我在别处见过 他在观察鲨鱼
It's a shark tower. I saw one in Florida. He's looking for sharks.
对不起 这是个暸望塔
Excuse me, dear, it's an observation platform.
他是我们的警长 他只不过在观望
That's our chief of police. He's just checking it.
那塔通常用来观鸟 看天气
Normally, it's used for… birdwatching, weather… measurements.
观察自然景色之类…
and nature observation, that sort of thing.
爱伦 我们的行程有点落后了
Excuse me. Ellen, we're running a little late.
爱伦
Ellen?
我们先上车 然后去参观乡村俱乐部…
If we all get on the bus, we could show you the country club…
快上来！所有的人都离开水面
Out of the water! Out of the water, now! Everybody out!
快上岸！离开水面！
Get out! Get out of there!
快上岸！
Get out!
那个笨蛋在搞什么？
What the hell is that idiot doing?
快出来！
Everybody out!
离开水面！快！都上岸！
Get out of there! Get out!
都上岸！
Everyone out!
快上岸！快上岸！
Out of the water! Get out of there! Get out!
离开水面！快！
Get out! Get out!
只不过是蓝鱼
It's just bluefish!
一群蓝鱼！
Bluefish! Chief, it's a school of bluefish!
只不过是蓝鱼
It's just bluefish.
- 马丁，- 爱伦 没事儿
- Martin? - Ellen, it's all right.
别令事情恶化 走吧
Let's not make it worse, come on.
都过去了 我们去俱乐部吧
OK, it's all over. Let's get back to the club.
没事了
It's OK.
是…误报
It's just… It's a false alarm.
没事了 回去吧
It's all right, go back.
我的天啊
My God.
走吧 没事了
Come on, let's go. It's all over.
布莉 现在我不接电话
Polly, no calls now, huh?
富加迪？
Fogarty?
好的 接过来
OK, put him on.
喂 菲尔？
Yeah, Phil?
什么照片？
What pictures?
你在开玩笑？我马上来
You're kidding! I'll be right over.
这是奥卡
Yeah… it's the Orca.
好镜头 很快 1- 4
Good lens, too. Fast. 1- 4, I think.
- 注意到… - 你还有一些吗？
- Notice the fusion… - What else have you got?
我今早又冲洗了一些 还没有印出来
Over here. I exposed some more this morning, I haven't developed 'em yet.
是它 就是它
That's it. That's the one.
说曹操曹操就到
Speak of the devil.
马丁，这是个正式会议
Martin, this is an official meeting.
我很高兴你们都在 你们看
Good, I'm glad you're all here. Look at this.
富加迪刚冲的 从失踪潜水人相机内发现的
Fogarty just developed it. It's from the missing divers' camera.
海草？
Seaweed?
我不知道 是什么？
I don't know. What is it?
是在水底 难怪这么暗
It's underwater. That's why it's so dark.
我看不出什么
There's nothing I can see.
你在说什么？你看 是一条鲨鱼
What are you talking about? Look at this. That's a shark.
你看看那轮廓 那嘴 眼晴！
Look at the outline, the mouth, the eyes.
这是什么？对不起 我看不出
Is that what it is? Sorry, I just don't see it.
我也看不出
Neither do I.
马丁，可以是任何物体
Martin, it could be anything.
你们以为我不认识鲨鱼吗？
Are you telling me I don't know what a shark looks like?
这什么也不是 镜头里的什么东西
This is nothing. Something in the lens.
- 照的我屁股 - 对 是你的屁股
- Lens my ass. - Damn right it's your ass.
理智些
Be reasonable.
理智！跟他理智？
Reasonable! With him?
天啊！你们能不能听听他的意见？
Goddamn it, will you just listen to him?
你要理智 布迪
Be reasonable?! Look, Brody,
你在海滩引起了公众的恐慌
you started a panic on that beach.
你在那里开枪 会伤及无辜的
You shot up the place. God knows who you injured.
有人控告我们怎么办？你想过了没有？
What if somebody sues us? Did you think about that?
这会毁了我们
It could ruin us.
别担心会被控告
Don't worry about being sued.
如果像我认为的那样 这里会空无一人
If this is what I think it is, there won't be anybody here.
- 我们不要… - 不要什么 莱瑞？
- Now, let's not… - Let's not what, Larry?
莱瑞 算了 他不会听的
Larry, let's forget it. He won't listen.
- 很明显他已认定了 - 我是认定了
- It's obvious he's made up his mind. - You bet I have.
我告诉在座各位 那是条鲨鱼
I'm telling you and everybody here, that's a shark.
我认识鲨鱼 因为我曾近距离见过
And I know because I've seen one up close.
你们最好采取行动 我再也不想经历一次了
And you better do something because I won't go through that hell again.
马丁，请等一会儿 好吗？
Martin, could you wait here for a minute?
为什么？
For what?
请先坐一会儿
Please, just have a seat,
让我们仔细看看照片再作决定
while we look at the picture and make up our own minds.
好的 我坐下
All right. I'll have a seat.
这也是值得的
For what it's worth.
谢谢
Thank you.
各位 请
Gentlemen, please.
好
Yeah!
麦克
Hey, Mike.
我在市政厅见到你爸了
I saw your dad over at Town Hall.
我知道
I know.
他真的在沙滩上出丑了吗？
Did he really freak out on the town beach?
我不知道
I don't know.
你别理他们 都是些废话
Don't worry about them. It's all bullshit.
他们只不过聚在一起大发缪论
Hey, you know this is the only place where the garbage man delivers?
哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha.
- 有人想去灯塔吗？- 现在？
- Anyone wanna go to the lighthouse? - Now?
明天 或许呆一整天
Tomorrow. Maybe spend the day.
我爸在车库留下了几箱啤酒
My dad left some cases of beer in the garage.
- 还在吗？- 我们可以在船上渡假了！
- Is it still there? - It's kinda vacationing on my boat!
麦克 你也去吗？
Mike, are you going to go?
- 去 为什么不？- 你可能要在海滩漆厠所！
- Yeah, why not? - You might be painting toilets!
好笑！
Very funny.
- 我们去野餐吗？- 对 你带食物
- Are we going to have a picnic? - Yeah, you bring the food.
- 麦克？- 嗨
- Mike? - Hi.
我想跟你去灯塔
I'd like to go to the lighthouse with you.
我不敢肯定去不去
I'm not sure I can go.
我受到限制 我爸不准我用船
I'm grounded. Dad won't let me use my boat.
你总听你父母的话吗？
Do you always do what your parents tell you to?
- 不是 - 好 我们明早八点码头见
- No. - Good. I'll be at the dock at eight.
各位 八时正
Eight o'clock, everybody.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do.
什么事？要去参加葬礼吗？
Hey! What is this? A wake for a funeral?
- 你让我们吃惊 - 我一听到就赶来了
- You surprised us. - I came as soon as I heard.
他们只不过开除了我 并没有埋葬我
They only fired me, they didn't bury me.
- 宝贝儿 我回来了 - 我知道了
- Hello, baby, I'm home. - I know.
我知道你知道了
I know you know.
听着 我有东西送给你
Listen, I've got something for you.
这东西戴在你身上更适合 因为你很帅气
This will look better on you than me because you're a snappier dresser.
噢 你们在喝佳酿
Oh, hey! You're drinking the good stuff.
干一杯怎么样？为新警长干杯
How about a toast? A toast to the new chief.
新警长需要幸运之神的眷顾
Come on, the chief's going to need all the luck he can get.
不喝？好 一起喝吧
No? OK, we'll do it together.
为新警长干杯
A toast to the new chief.
为警长欢呼！
Hail to the chief.
喝吧！这是你职业的里程碑
Come on, drink! This is a milestone in your career.
- 放松 马丁，- 瞧 警长
- Ease up, Martin. - Look, Chief,
并不是我不想要你的工作
not only don't I want your job,
我是来说你是最威大的
but I came to tell you I think you're the greatest.
- 而我… - 杰夫 没事儿
- And I… - Oh, Jeff, it's OK.
来吧 我知道这不是你的错
Come on. It's not your fault, I know that.
嗯 我要走了
Well, I got to go anyway.
谢谢你来看我 杰夫
Thanks for coming by, Jeff.
- 你实在很帮忙 - 谢谢
- You've been a big help. - Thank you.
- 晚安 杰夫 - 晚安
- Good night, Jeff. - Good night.
可怜的韩卓，迟早也会被开除的
Poor Hendricks. They'll fire his ass, too.
等着瞧吧
You'll see.
我给他们看鲨鱼的照片
I showed them a picture of that shark.
他们不去看鲨鱼
They didn't see it.
他们只看他们想看的东西
They see only what they want to see.
但鲨鱼在那里
But it's out there, all right.
- 是个大傢伙 - 他们因此开除了你？
- It's a big mother, too. - Is that why they fired you?
不仅仅是这些
It wasn't just that.
还有什么？沙滩事件？我在现场
What was it? The beach? I saw what happened.
我开枪了！开枪了！
Oh, I blew it. I blew it.
我口没遮挡 枪没遮挡
I shot off my mouth. I shot off my gun.
四年的辛劳
Four years down the drain.
一枪皆失
Shot to hell.
真是个笨蛋
What a dummy.
还有什么事？
What else?
还有什么事
我以前从未被开除过
I've never been fired before.
你知道吗？
You know that?
我是说 我十七岁时有过一次
I mean, once when I was 17, when I was a kid, yeah.
但正式工作从未开除过
But… never from a real job.
没有人说我不胜任
Nobody ever told me I couldn't hack it.
他们不是这个意思
They're not saying that.
他们是这个意思
Yes, they are.
是这个意思
They are.
也许他们说得对
Maybe they're right.
我很疲倦
I'm tired.
很累
Tired.
实在太累了
I'm too damn tired.
喝得太多了
Too damn drunk.
你现在喝得太多了
That's what you are, too damn drunk.
- 你要出去吗？- 对
- Are you going out? - Yeah.
你要出海吗？
Going sailing?
- 可能吧 - 带我去
- Maybe. - Take me.
不行！
No!
- 我想跟你去 轻 - 点儿
- I wanna go with you. - Shh! Quiet!
麦克！
Michael.
好 来吧 但要轻一点儿！
All right. Come on. But be quiet!
嗨 丹尼斯 我的至爱
Hello, Denise, love of my life.
如果你被关禁闭了 我们做什么？练习？
If you're grounded, what are we doing? Practice?
对 练习
Yeah, practice.
为啥在这里？去沙滩吧 我们可以找个姑娘聊聊
Why are we here and not the beach? We can fool around, pick up some girls.
你再碍事我就赶你回家
If you're gonna get in the way, go home.
我没碍事 我碍事吗 安迪？
I'm not in the way. Andy, am I in the way?
你总是碍事
You're always in the way.
他惹麻烦了吗？
Is he causing trouble?
放下我
Put me down!
- 你可以上我的船 - 好！
- You can go out in my boat. - Yeah!
你想要他？请自便
You want him? You can have him.
我想你让某人很高兴
I think you just made somebody very happy.
- 嗨 朋友 - 嗨
- Hi guys. - Hi.
- 麦克 你要出海？- 我以为你关禁闭了
- Mike, you going out? - I thought you were grounded.
- 我想去就能去 - 你能？
- I can go out if I want to. - He can.
船能装得下我们吗？
Is there enough room for all of us on the boat?
- 不知道 我们… - 肯定能装下
- I don't know, we're… - There's plenty of room.
我猜也能
I guess so.
布露？我有地方
Brooke? I've got room.
好极了！
Great!
- 你跟我去吗？- 当然
- You'll go with me? - Sure.
谢谢你们 我要跟蒂姆出海
Thanks guys, but I'm going with Timmy. Come on.
太好了！
Fantastic!
- 是个大错误 - 别担心
- It's a big mistake. - Don't worry.
来吧 我已经准备好了
Come on, you guys, I'm ready.
她不是说跟我们去吗？
You said she was coming with us.
很明显 她不来了
Well, obviously, she's not.
- 你想谈谈此事吗？- 你想游泳回家吗？
- You wanna talk about it? - You wanna swim home?
- 嗨 汤姆！- 尼古拉斯 你应该在上课
- Hey, Tom! - Nicholas! You should be in class.
我有个伴侣！
I've got company!
- 我要去捉龙虾 - 好 捉一只给我！
- I'm going for lobster. - Great! Bring me one!
- 我要用牛油炒的 - 听到吗 汤姆？
- I want mine with butter. - Got that, Tom?
再见 火鸡
So long, turkeys.
今天斯巴凯将带你们潜水
Sparky will take you down today.
准备好了就下水
If you're ready, let's buddy-up and drop.
拉我们上去！拉我们上去！
Get us in! For Christ's sake, get us in.
送他上去 保持他的体温
Let's get him in and keep him warm.
送他到甲板上
Put him in the forward cabin.
我看他没事 没事
He'll be OK. Things'll be OK.
我们出发！
Let's go.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了？
So?
我回办公室收拾一下办公桌
So, I'll go down to the office, clean out the desk,
交还警车
turn in the truck,
或许会受到你上司的冷言冷语
and maybe get shitfaced and rap your boss in the mouth.
我也该辞职了
I better give notice.
别太在乎 我们得有收入啊
Take it easy. We may need the income.
麦克出去了
Mike's gone.
他近来一直早出 已经习惯了
He's making out early these days, must be a morning man.
像他父亲
Like his father.
早安 有什么特别的事吗？
Good morning. Anything special today?
没有 尚出去玩了 他喜欢去哪里就去哪里
No. Sean's out somewhere. Let him have whatever he wants.
- 但别让他吃糖果 - 好的
- Just keep him away from the candy. - OK.
- 我还可以搭便车吗？- 嗯嗯
- Do I still get my ride? - Mmm.
让你修水管的弟弟 来修修楼上的水槽
Call your brother, the plumber, that sink upstairs is screwed up.
法兰？他是我表弟
Frankie? He's my cousin.
问他需要学徒工吗？
Ask if he can use an apprentice.
一切顺利
Have a nice day.
你想让它这个样子吗？
Do you want to just leave her pointing up?
等一会
I'm on it.
好了 这里不错
There we go. Yeah, this is fine.
不是要扬帆吗？
What about sailing?
那又怎么了？
What about it?
别担心 我们会扬帆的
Don't you worry. We're gonna make it.
不小心 你会漂到布达佩斯的
We'll make it to Budapest if you're not careful!
其他的人呢？
Hey, what about the others?
其他的人？
What about them?
我们到时 他们定会在那里
They'll be there when we get there.
他们会点起篝火 海货 酒
They'll have their bonfire, clams, liquor…
是吗？
Yeah?
我们现在做什么呢？
What are we gonna do in the meantime?
我们现在来想一下儿
Well, in the meantime, we'll have to think of something.
等等
Wait a minute.
什么？
What?
拿毯子出来
Get out the blanket.
要是我的屁股脏了 我妈妈会不高兴的
I got black marks all over my butt and mom's getting uptight about it.
好
OK.
毯子来了
Out with the blanket.
你真的需要毯子吗？
You really need a blanket?
我不需要！
I don't need one!
这儿 你的毯子
Well… here's your blanket.
阿迪！救命呀！
Eddie! Help!
阿迪！
Eddie!
- 迪娜！- 救救我！
- Tina! - Help me!
迪娜！
Tina!
天啊！
Oh… Jesus.
阿迪 快游！有鲨鱼
Eddie, swim! Swim fast, it's a shark, Eddie.
游啊！
Swim!
上帝 阿迪！快点游！
Oh, God. Eddie, swim!
快点游！快
Swim faster! Hurry!
快 快点游！
Come on! Swim!
阿迪！是条鲨鱼！
Hurry, Eddie. It's a shark!
阿迪 快！快！快游！
Eddie, hurry! Faster! Come on. Swim!
快 快 阿迪！
Hurry! Hurry, Eddie.
阿迪！
Eddie!
迪娜
Tina…
啊，妈呀…
Oh, Mama…
赶它走！
Please make it go away.
Make it go away.
赶它走！
Make it go away!
现在不是你的职责了
Honey, it's not your job any more.
我只想过去看看
I just wanna look.
快 驶开！快！
Come on, get out of there! Come on.
- 他怎么了？- 血栓 血里有气泡
- What happened to him? - Embolism. Air bubbles in the blood.
他上升的速度太快了
He came up too fast, Chief.
一定在水底受惊了
Something must have scared him.
他只是受了惊吓
He just panicked.
别担心 我们会好好照顾他的
Don't worry, we're taking good care of him.
怎样会这样？
How did this happen?
被咬伤的 像痉挛
Bite reflex, like a spasm.
是在孩子出海后
It happened after the kids went out.
什么孩子？
What kids?
小云汉 布露 杰克 麦克…
Junior Vaughan, Brookie Peters, Jackie, Mike…
我们的麦克？
Our Mike?
他们要去灯塔
They're headed for the lighthouse. Hey!
警长 你已经不是警长了 我不能让你驾船出海
Look, Chief, you're not chief now. I can't let you take her out.
布迪太太 你也不能出海
Mrs Brody, look, you can't go. Neither one of you can go.
- 捡起那个绳索 - 麦克在那里
- Get that line. - Mike is out there.
但我签收这条船了 布迪太太
But I signed for the boat. Mrs Brody, please.
妈的！警长 你错了
Shit! Chief, go on up to the bow, you're doing that wrong.
应去船头 解船头缆
Go ahead, untie the bowline.
他们不会开除俩人
They can't fire both of us, right?
总得有个管事的
Somebody's got to be in charge.
好了 你想去哪个方向？
All right, which direction do you wanna go?
你说过灯塔
You said something about a lighthouse.
好的
All right.
阿米堤呼叫海港巡逻
Amity Launch to Harbour Patrol.
这是海港巡逻
This is Harbour Patrol.
能否安排一架直升机？
Listen, do you think you can raise me a chopper?
是布迪吗？暂时不能
Is that you Brody? Not right away.
它正在检察浮标
It's out checking a buoy.
通知它前往灯塔
Get it out to the lighthouse.
有些孩子去了那里 要将他们接回海港
There's some kids sailing out there. I want them back in port.
知道了 将孩子接回
Affirmative. Turn the kids back to port.
巡逻队话毕
I heard you. Patrol out.
布迪话毕
Brody out.
快点儿 笨蛋 你们落后了
Hurry up, suckers, you're dragging!
我们越过灯塔吧 我知道个好地方
Hey, let's go past the lighthouse. I know a better spot. Come about.
听你的
You got it!
我抓到了 警长
I got it, Chief.
没事 别紧张
It's all right. Come on.
没事
It's OK.
没事了
It's all right.
不
No.
爱伦
Ellen.
不 不
No, no.
迪娜 迪娜…
Tina, Tina…
迪娜！… 没事
Tina, it's OK.
- 它还在那里 - 什么
- It's still there. - What is?
什么还在那里？
What's still there?
鲨 鲨 鲨 鲨…
Sh-sh-sh-sh…
鲨鱼！
Shark!
还在那
It's still there.
那条船会送你回去 他们去哪里了？
That boat will take you in. Where the hell are they?
右弦十度 朝着沙丘…
Ten degrees off your starboard. Take a heading…
废话！指出来！
Not that shit! Point!
在那边
There.
我知道了
All right, I got it.
克里斯芬先生
Mr Christian! Mr Christian!
给这个船充充气 刮掉可笑的胡子
Pump up this boat! And shave off that dreadful moustache.
英格兰希望每个人尽职 准备好就开火！
England expects every man to do his duty. Fire when ready!
该死的鱼雷！全速前进！
Damn the torpedoes! Full speed ahead!
最光荣的时刻
This will be our finest hour.
妈的！
Oh, shit.
哇 有人刺破了你的气球？
Hey, Bligh, someone pop your balloon?
没问题 没问题
No problem, no problem.
保持平衡！
Balance the boat!
小心！
Watch out!
做点儿什么！
Do something!
蒂姆！布露！
Timmy! Brooke!
小心！
Hey! Look out.
它在哪里？
Where is it?
- 把我带走！- 我会的
- Get me out of here! - I'll get you out.
莱瑞！
Larry!
莱瑞！转！
Larry! Turn!
转！
Turn!
没事
It's OK.
- 快！- 快帮麦克
- Hurry up! - Mike's out there.
快出来
Out of the water.
快来帮麦克！
Somebody look out for Mike!
抓住点儿东西！
Hang on to something!
麦克 过来！
Mike, get out of there!
坚持住！
Hold on!
啊，天啊！
Oh, my God.
麦克！
Mike!
布迪！
Brody!
就这样
That's it.
- 抓住胳膊 - 快
- Get his arm. - Come on.
抓住他的外衣！
Pull his jacket!
拉上来 它来了
Get him clear, it's coming up.
快！快！
Come on! Come on!
该死！
Shit!
他流了很多血
He's bleeding pretty bad.
要送麦克去见医生
We got to get Mike to a doctor.
你的船能开吗？
Can you sail?
能 让他进来
Yeah. We'll take him in.
好 快去找援兵
OK. Get some help here fast.
我们走
Let's go.
我们来收拾这个残局
Let's wrap this mess up.
把它扔给布露
Throw this to Brooke.
布露 接住，再抛给马克
Brooke, get this and throw it to Mark.
马克 接住
Here, take it.
把它绑在船桅上
Tie a bowline around your mast.
放松
Easy.
快 拉
Come on, pull.
不知道能否支持住
I don't know if it'll hold.
好 把船垫装上
All right. Someone put a fender up.
我们可以用另一手
We could use another hand on this.
别紧张 尽管拉
Take it easy. Just pull.
绑好它 好
Tie it off. All right.
阿米堤号呼叫空中巡逻
Amity Launch to Air Patrol One.
听到了吗？
Do you read me?
这是空中巡逻 你是布迪吗？
'This is Air Patrol. That you, Brody?
你找到孩子的位置了吗？
Yeah. Do you have a fix on those kids?
没有 我仍在搜索
Negative. I'm still down.
你要尽快呀 他们孤立无援
Get the hell up because I'm out here alone.
布迪 我要调校频道
Brody, I got to switch frequencies.
通知我上司 我在法兰斯浅滩与你会合
Call my boss. I'll meet you by Francis Shoal. Out.
法兰斯浅滩？在哪里？
Francis Shoal? Where the hell is Francis Shoal?
妈的！
Shit.
我孤军作战
I'm all alone out here.
有谁要玩游戏吗？
Anyone want to play charades?
没有
No.
我们只需到电缆塔等候就行了
All we have to do is land at Cable Junction and wait.
这个破船怎么能漂过去？
How will we do that on this garbage?
过了电缆塔是什么地方？
What's after Cable Junction?
大西洋 然后是爱尔兰
The Atlantic. Then Ireland.
上帝 我肚子饿了
God, I'm hungry.
海港巡逻
Air Patrol to Base.
空中巡逻呼叫基地 已发现那班航海者的位置
I have a positive location on that sailing party.
船被损 在海中漂浮
Disabled and adrift,
大约在电缆塔以西四分之三里
about three quarters of a mile west of Cable Junction,
风浪将他们吹向东面
wind and tide carrying them due east.
大家怎么样？有人受伤了吗？
Is everyone OK? Is anybody hurt?
没有
No!
我会拖你们前往电缆塔
I'll tow you to Cable Junction,
然后通知海防队
then call the Coast Guard.
扔根绳子给我
Throw me a line.
别紧张 可以了
Take it easy. Here we go.
- 啊，倒霉的一天 - 好了！
- Oh, what a day - Here you go!
好了
OK.
- 抓住点儿东西 - 好
- Now, hold on to something. - OK.
- 快！- 最好快点儿
- Hurry up! - Better hang on.
尚
Sean.
- 尚 - 尚
- Sean! - Sean!
尚
Sean!
尚！
快拉他上船
Get him in the boat.
- 尚 - 快！
- Sean! - Come on!
上船！
Get aboard.
- 快！- 来啊！
- Hurry! - Come on.
快
Come on.
我站不起来
I can't get up.
不
No!
送她到医院后来我办公室
Take her to the hospital and meet me at the office.
要明白我的处境…
Try to understand my position…
迪娜不会有事 你没事吧？
Tina will be all right. Are you OK?
爱伦 对不起 相信我 真的对不起
Ellen, I'm sorry. Believe me, I'm sorry.
我只在想…
I was only thinking of…
我不管你想什么
I don't give a damn what you think.
我只知道死了一个孩子 而我儿子和丈夫仍在海上
A boy is dead and my son and husband are still out there.
阿米堤号呼叫海港巡逻
Amity Launch to Harbour Patrol.
阿米堤号呼叫海港…
Amity Launch to Harbour…
妈的！
Damn it!
尚 抓住绳索！
Sean, catch the rope!
- 快 绳索！- 尚！
- Come on, the rope! - Sean!
尚！抓住绳索！
Sean, catch the rope!
尚 绳索！
Sean, the rope!
- 来 尚！- 来 尚！
- Come on, Sean! - Come on, Sean!
来！
Come on!
尚！
Sean!
尚 抓住绳索！
Sean, catch the rope!
绳子！尚！
The rope, Sean!
来！尚！
Come on, Sean!
他要人帮忙 否则不会成功
Come on! You've gotta help or it won't work.
你能否住嘴？
Will you stop?
来 醒醒 尚！
Come on, Sean, wake up!
捡起来！
Pick it up!
尚！
Sean!
尚！该死！
Sean, goddamn it.
尚！听着 否则踢烂你的屁股
Sean, listen to me or I'll break your ass!
好 来
OK, come on.
好 尚 听着
OK, Sean, now listen.
我们将绳索抛给你 你抓住它
We'll throw you this rope and you better catch it.
尚 准备好了吗？
Sean, you ready?
来了 小朋友
Here it comes, kid.
接住！尚！
Get it, Sean.
尚！接住
Sean, get it.
快 接住
Come on, get it.
好 把它绑在甲板上
Good. Now tie it around the centreboard.
绑紧点儿
Tie it tight.
好了 抓住
You ready? Hang on.
抓住
Hold on.
抓住，好吗？
Hang on, OK?
来了 抓紧点儿
Here we go. Hold on tight.
好了
OK, kid.
别紧张
Take it easy.
快
Come on.
好
OK.
- 救他上来！- 快
- Get him out! - Come on.
感谢上帝
Oh, God. Are you OK, kid?
还以为失去了你
I thought we lost you.
电缆塔就在前面
Cable Junction's ahead.
- 我们能到达那里吗？- 不知道？
- Can we make it? - I don't know.
- 我只是问问 - 我知道
- Hey, I was just asking! - I know.
她怎么样了？
How's she doing?
要保持她的体温
Just got to keep her warm.
快来帮忙 我可以开动它
Somebody help me and we could steer this.
你们还指望能开船？
What are you playing with a tube for?
- 如果我们… - 闭嘴！
- If everyone… - Shut up!
对不起 我不能不去想！
I'm sorry but I can't stop thinking about this!
你最好不要！
Well, you better try!
上帝 请帮帮我们
Oh, God, please help.
上帝…
Jesus…
圣母玛利亚
Holy Mary,
耶稣之母亲
Mother of Christ,
请救救我们
please help us.
请帮帮我们.
Please help us.
我们乞求
We're begging.
请拯救我们
Please save us.
感谢耶稣
Oh, thank Christ.
将它绑在后面
Here, take that back to the cleat.
- 怎么啦？- 我没事
- What happened? - I'm OK.
- 真没事？- 鲨鱼袭击了我们
- Sure? - A shark hit us.
尚在那里
Sean's out there.
- 什么 - 他要来 没事吧？
- What? - He wanted to come.
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
他们在电缆塔附近
They're in the current heading for Cable Junction.
好 到灯塔上等我 好吗？
All right, get to the lighthouse and stay there, OK?
- 呆在那里 - 对不起 爸爸
- Stay there. - I'm sorry, Dad.
别提了 只管去灯塔吧
Forget it. Just get to the lighthouse.
- 我们快到了 - 我看不行
- We're almost there. - It's not gonna work.
快转 往左
Come on, more to port.
继续前进 我们定会成功
Keep it going. We'll make it.
往左 该死！
More to port, goddamn it!
一直过来
All the way over.
莱瑞 我们能登上岛吗？
Larry, are we going to make it to the island?
我们正在努力
We're steering for it, kid.
但风从侧面吹来
But the wind drift is lateral.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是我们偏离航道 我们往那里漂去
It means that we're going sideways. We're going that way.
- 但我们正朝目标前进 - 现在不是
- We were heading right for it. - Not now.
该死！该死！
Shit. Shit, shit, shit.
等等 别划水了
Wait! Stop paddling.
- 为什么上岛？- 鲨鱼！
- What about the island? - The shark!
- 怎么了？- 我想我们搁浅了
- What's happening? - I think we're stuck.
我看是海底
It's just the bottom.
- 不 是它 - 是海底
- It's that thing. - It's just the bottom.
不是海底 是它！他要吃了我们！
No, it's not the bottom. It's that thing! It's gonna kill us!
杰凯 闭嘴！
Jackie, shut up!
- 不！它要吃了我们！- 闭嘴！闭嘴！
- No! It's going to kill us! - Shut up! Shut up!
放开她！
Leave her alone!
那你去照顾她
Then you take care of her.
- 她歇斯底里 打… - 坐下
- She's hysterical, beating… - Sit down.
肃静！
Be quiet!
- 闭嘴！- 听着！
- Shut up! - Listen!
- 她不是瞎说 - 听着
- She shouldn't freak out. - Listen!
你们听到了吗？
You hear it?
在那边！朝我们这里来了
Over there! It's coming towards us.
是爸爸！爸爸！
It's Dad! Dad!
爸爸！
Dad!
冷静 来…
Oh, cool. Cool, come on…
拉自己过来 我们离开这里
Pull yourselves over and we'll get out of here.
不行 我们被卡住了
We can't. We're stuck on the bottom here.
我靠近点儿你们就能登船
I'll get you closer. We'll come aboard.
- 侧面靠近 - 快点！
- Pull us alongside. - Please hurry!
好了 稳住它
All right, hold it steady.
哇 鲨
Oh, sh…!
等等
Wait!
爸爸！
Dad!
我没事 你们别动
I'm all right. Hold on.
救生筏
接着它 我帮你们过来
All right, take this and I'll get you over.
- 好 绑好它 - 好的
- All right, tie it on. - OK.
好 将绳子穿过环
All right, pull these hooks over with the rope.
然后固定在筏子上 我用绞车拉你们过来
Secure them to the raft then I'll pull you back with the winch, OK?
好
OK.
好了 可以拉了
All right, pull it over.
卡住了
It's stuck.
等等 我开倒车
Wait a minute, I'll put… I'll put it in reverse.
露西！
Lucy!
露西！小心！
Lucy, look out!
我的天啊！不！不！
Oh, my God! No! No!
露西！
Lucy!
不
No!
啊，上帝！不
Oh, my God! No!
爸爸！
Dad!
不要动！
Hold on!
（高压 不得靠近）
爸爸！
Dad!
走开！
Get away!
不！
No!
走开！
Get away!
不
No!
尚
Sean!
- 它在哪里？- 它在哪里？
- Where'd he go? - Where is he?
- 在那里！- 在那里！
- There he is! - Over there.
你在做什么？
What the hell are you doing?
快走开！
Get out of there!
它正向你游去！
He's heading right for you!
来吧！杂种！
All right, you big bastard, come on.
我有个礼物要送给你
I got something for you now.
对了 来吧
That's it! That a boy! Come on!
就在这里！
Right over here!
爸爸！
Dad!
对了 来
That's it. Come on.
快走开！
No! Get out of the way!
别那样！
Don't do it!
走开！走开！
Get away! Get away!
爸爸！小心呀！
Dad! Watch out!
来！
Come on!
小心！
Look out!
张开大嘴吧！
Open wide!
张开大嘴吧！说「啊」！
Open wide, say "ah"!
他成功了 他成功了！
He did it. He got it!
他成功了！成功了！
He did it! He did it! He did it!
你看见吗？它死了？
Did he get it? It's dead?
它死了！
It's dead!
啊，谢谢
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你 谢谢… 谢谢你
Thank you, thank you, thank you…
- 你呢… - 是他们要我出海的
- And you… - They made me go with them.
一定是的
Sure they did!